omilab.org 2019-02-28

# OMiLAB NPO

## Privacy Policy

  1. Home
  2. Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

The OMiLAB gGmbH takes data protection very seriously and is committed to collecting and using all personal data in accordance with the relevant data protection legislation. In this data protection policy, we would like to explain which data we process for what purpose and in which way and how we protect your data.

OMiLAB gGmbH  
Lützowufer 1  
10785 Berlin  
Germany  
Phone: 0049 30 26 36 78 63  
Email: info [@] omilab.org  

Elena-Teodora Miron, elena.miron [@] omilab.org 

You have the following rights towards us regarding your personal data:

• Right to information,  
• Right to correction or deletion,  
• Right to restrict processing,  
• Right to object to the processing,  
• Right to data transferability.

Please send an email to info@omilab.org in order to exercise one or more of the aforementioned rights.  
If you believe that the processing of personal data concerning you violates the GDPR, you have the right of appeal to a supervisory authority, without prejudice to any other remedies. 

If you have given your consent to the processing of your data, you can revoke this at any time. Such revocation affects the permissibility of processing your personal data after you have given it to us.  
If we base the processing of your personal data on the balancing of interests, you may object to the processing. This is the case if processing is not necessary, in particular, to fulfil a contract with you, which is described by us in the following description of the functions. When exercising such objection, we ask you to explain the reasons why we should not process your personal data as we have done. In the event of your justified objection, we will examine the situation and either stop or adjust data processing or point out to you our compelling reasons for protection, on the basis of which we will continue processing.  
Of course, you can object to the processing of your personal data for purposes of advertising and data analysis at any time. You can inform us about your advertising contradiction under the following contact data: info@omilab.org 

You may use the website at any time without registering. When using the website for information purposes only, i.e. if you do not register or otherwise provide us with information, we only collect the personal data that your browser transmits to our server. If you wish to view our website, we collect the following data, which are technically necessary for us to display our website to you and to provide stability and security (legal basis is Art. 6 para. 1 s. 1 lit. f GDPR):

• IP address  
• date and time of the request  
• time zone difference to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)  
• content of the request (specific page)  
• access status/HTTP status code  
• the amount of data transferred in each case  
• website from which the request comes  
• Browser  
• operating system and its surface  
• language and version of the browser software.

In addition to the aforementioned data, cookies are stored on your computer when you use our website (see below the description in section “Cookies”). Cookies are small text files that are stored on your hard disk in the browser you use. Through these cookies we receive certain information from you. Cookies cannot run programs or transmit viruses to your computer. They serve to make the website more user-friendly and effective overall.  

This website uses the following types of cookies, the scope and functionality of which are explained below:  
• Transient cookies,  
• Persistent cookies.  
Transient cookies are automatically deleted when you close your browser. This includes in particular the session cookies. These store a so-called session ID, with which different requests of your browser can be assigned to the common session. This will allow your computer to be recognized when you return to our portal. Session cookies are deleted when you log out or close your browser.  
Persistent cookies are automatically deleted after a specified period, which may vary depending on the cookie. You can delete cookies at any time in the security settings of your browser.  
You can configure your browser settings according to your wishes and, for example, refuse the acceptance of third party cookies or all cookies. Please note that you may not be able to use all functions of this portal.  
We use cookies to identify you for follow-up visits if you have an account with us. Otherwise you would have to log in again for each visit. 

In addition to the purely informational use of our portal, we offer various services which you can use if you are interested. As a rule, you must provide further personal data, which we use to provide the respective service and to which the aforementioned data processing principles apply.  
In some cases, we use external service providers to process your data. These have been carefully selected and commissioned by us, are bound by our instructions and are regularly checked.  
Furthermore, we may pass on your personal data to third parties if we offer services in cooperation with partners. For further information, please provide your personal data or refer to the description of the offer below.  
If our service providers or partners are based in a country outside the European Economic Area (EEA), we will inform you of the consequences of this circumstance in the description of the offer. 

We currently use the following social media plug-ins: Facebook and LinkedIn. You can recognize the provider of the plug-in by the marking on the box above its initial letter or the logo. We offer you the possibility to communicate directly with the provider of the plug-in via the button. Only if you click on the marked field and thereby activate it, the plug-in provider receives the information that you have accessed the corresponding website of our online offer. In addition, the data specified in the section “General use of our portal” will be transmitted. In the case of Facebook, the IP address is anonymized immediately after collection, according to the respective provider in your country. By activating the plug-in, personal data is transferred from you to the respective plug-in provider and stored there (for US providers in the USA). Since the plug-in provider collects data mainly via cookies, we recommend that you delete all cookies before clicking on the grayed-out box using your browser's security settings.  
We have no influence on the data collected and data processing processes, nor are we aware of the full extent of data collection, the purposes of processing, the storage periods. We also have no information on the deletion of the data collected by the plug-in provider. The plug-in provider stores the data collected about you as user profiles and uses these for the purposes of advertising, market research and/or demand-oriented design of its website. Such an evaluation takes place in particular (also for not logged in users) for the representation of demand-fair advertisement and in order to inform other users of the social network about your activities on our website. You have a right of objection to the creation of these user profiles, whereby you must contact the respective plug-in provider to exercise this right. Through the plug-ins we offer you the possibility to interact with social networks and other users, so that we can improve our offer and make it more interesting for you as a user. The legal basis for the use of the plug-ins is Art. 6 para. 1 s. 1 lit. f GDPR.  
The data is passed on regardless of whether you have an account with the plug-in provider and are logged in there. If you are logged in with the plug-in provider, your data collected with us will be directly assigned to your existing account with the plug-in provider. If you click the activated button and, for example, link the page, the plug-in provider also stores this information in your user account and shares it publicly with your contacts. We recommend that you log out regularly after using a social network, especially before activating the button, as this way you can avoid being assigned to your profile with the plug-in provider.  
Further information on the purpose and scope of data collection and its processing by the plug-in provider can be found in the data protection declarations of these providers notified below. They will also provide you with further information about your rights in this regard and setting options to protect your privacy.  
Addresses of the respective plug-in providers and URL with their data protection information:  
Facebook Inc., 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, California 94304, USA; http://www.facebook.com/policy.php; further information on data collection:  
http://www.facebook.com/help/186325668085084,  
http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other#applications and  
http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info#everyoneinfo.   
Facebook has submitted to the EU-US Privacy Shield, https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework.  
LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, California 94043, USA; http://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy.   
LinkedIn has submitted to the EU-US Privacy Shield, https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework. 

We process and store your personal data only for the period necessary to achieve the storage purpose or insofar as required pursuant to applicable laws. If the storage purposes ceases to apply or if a storage period stipulated by applicable laws expires, the personal data is routinely blocked or deleted in accordance with the statutory provisions.  
The criterion for the duration of the storage of your personal data is the respective legal retention period. After expiry of this period, the corresponding data will be routinely deleted, provided that they are no longer required for contract fulfilment or contract initiation or other legitimate interests.

You can have your data deleted by us if you send us a respective email to info@omilab.org 

Registered users will be informed and asked for consent by email in case of any changes to this data protection policy. The data protection policy can be printed out or saved at any time.  
Contact details:  
We take your comments about our data protection policy very seriously. If you have any questions about this policy, or feel that it is not being adhered to, please get in touch with us in confidence at any time using the following contact details:  
Please send an email to info@omilab.org or write to  
OMiLAB gGmbH  
Elena-Teodora Miron  
Lützowufer 1  
10785 Berlin  
Germany
